zarafa.com 2014-11-28

# Zarafa Privacy Policy | www.zarafa.com

**Purpose and Scope**  
This policy discloses what information we gather when visiting zarafa.com or buy products directly from us. It describes how we use that information and how you can control it.

**Information Zarafa gathers and tracks**  
Zarafa collects two kinds of information from users:

  1. data which users volunteer by signing up to receive news and product information, entering contests, completing surveys, or buying directly from us;
  2. aggregated tracking data we collect when users interact with Zarafa.

**Personal information**  
We use the personal information you provide voluntarily to send information you've requested and to fulfill orders. The specific use of your personal information varies, depending on the way you contact us:

  * When you subscribe to Zarafa mailing lists to receive Zarafa news and product information, you must provide email address. We never sell or rent your email address you provide when subscribing to our lists. Please note that Zarafa mailing lists are archived by several third party sites and your email address can be found from their archives. Zarafa doesn't have control over those archives.
  * When you order Zarafa commercial licenses, or purchase commercial support, or buy training, we add you to our mailing lists and will contact you in Zarafa related issues now and then.
  * When you enter a contest or survey, we may ask for your name, address, and email address so we can administer the contest and notify winners.

We release personal information when we believe that release is appropriate to comply with the law, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Zarafa , our users, or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

In addition, Zarafa and its' partners may engage in joint events or resell each others' products. Such promotions will always reference the partners involved. Both Zarafa and the partner(s) will have access to that information.

**Aggregated tracking information**  
We analyse visitors' use of our sites by tracking information such as pageviews, traffic flow, search terms, and click through. We use this information to improve our sites. We also share this anonymous traffic and demographic information in aggregate form with advertisers and other business partners. We do not share any information with advertisers that can identify an individual user.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifile information.

**Cookies**  
As part of our approach to providing personalized services on our web site, Zarafa may use cookies in the future to store and sometimes track information from you. A cookie is a small data file sent to your browser from a web server to be stored on your hard drive that allows easier access the next time the same page is visited. For example, a cookie is sent when you register or sign in to this site. With your consent, cookies can store information from forms you fill out to create a user profile so that you do not have to re-enter the information each time you visit. Right now Zarafa does not use cookies!

If you do not want your personal information to be stored by cookies, you can configure your browser so that it notifies you whenever a cookie is received so you can decide each time if you accept them or not. However, the use of cookies may be necessary to provide certain features and choosing to reject cookies may reduce the functionality of the site. Your browser help should include precise instructions explaining how to define the acceptance of cookies.

Our website also automatically captures IP addresses. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our website, and to help ensure the security of your interaction with the website.

**Services**  
This site contains links to other sites. Zarafa is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other web sites.

**Contests & Surveys**  
We may run contests or surveys on our site in which we ask our users for contact information (like their email address). We use the customer contact information from the entry form to send the user information out our company and its products, or to contact them when it becomes necessary (notices like, updates, patches, etc...). Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings (see the choice/opt-out section below).

**Security**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. All the data regarding users, their computers' system information and benchmark results are stored on a server. This server is located in a locked and guarded space and only authorised Zarafa personnel have access to the database containing given user names and passwords.

**Notification of Changes**  
If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on [www.zarafa.com](http://www.zarafa.com/ "www.zarafa.com"). If we decide to use personally identifile information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users via email. Users will be able to opt out of any new use of their personal information.

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and from our partners at the point where we request information out the user.  
This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our datase so they no longer receive future communications or access to our other services:

  1. You can send email to [webmaster@zarafa.com](mailto:webmaster@zarafa.com), stating your request.
  2. You can reply to any unwanted communications that you receive, stating your request.

**Reviewing personal data**  
You can review and validate the information which we have collected from you by sending an email to [webmaster@zarafa.com](mailto:webmaster@zarafa.com) and requesting a review of your personal data.

**Contacting the Web Site**  
If you have any questions or comments out of this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact [webmaster@zarafa.com](mailto:webmaster@zarafa.com).

**WebApp feedback  
**In the product Zarafa WebApp, end users have the possibility to send feedback directly to Zarafa. This feedback, including any attachments, passed to Zarafa this way will be stored, analyzed and handled to improve the quality and usefulness of the software. It will not be made public in any way. You may optionally provide contact details, which are not used in any way except to communicate about this feedback. With the feedback, the following information is also sent to Zarafa: the version of WebApp and the Zarafa server, the brand and version of the browser, screen resolution and the URL WebApp is used from. You can request removal of this information by sending an e-mail to [webmaster@zarafa.com](mailto:webmaster@zarafa.com). By clicking " _Submit_ " or " _Send_ " in either the " _Features Submitter_ " widget, the " _Bug Reporter_ " widget, or the window that is created when clicking the " _Feedback?_ " button, you agree to these terms
